<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-11-07T22:19:58+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Ruuben Lambrechts</title><entry><title type="html">dope on cotton</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/08/01/dopeoncotton.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="dope on cotton" /><published>2017-08-01T15:28:47+02:00</published><updated>2017-08-01T15:28:47+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/08/01/dopeoncotton</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/08/01/dopeoncotton.html">&lt;p&gt;The images below are some examples of designs I made during the time I worked at dope on cotton. My own T-shirt design that I created was the cotton plant. I made different variations on the design depending on what color of T-shirt it would go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also created a design for the gay parade in Antwerp, I chose different gay symbols or people that support the gay community and looked for silhouettes of them. I placed those in a 4x4 grid and placed a quote of Freddie Mercury below.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The images below are some examples of designs I made during the time I worked at dope on cotton. My own T-shirt design that I created was the cotton plant. I made different variations on the design depending on what color of T-shirt it would go.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MSK gent</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/31/msk.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MSK gent" /><published>2017-05-31T15:28:47+02:00</published><updated>2017-05-31T15:28:47+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/31/msk</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/31/msk.html">&lt;p&gt;We started with interviewing people in the streets of Ghent and asked about what they knew about the MSK, and what their interests were in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a full week of brainstorming We found a concept that was based on traveling. With our campaign we want to tell the youth, that you don’t have to travel to see art, because it is just around the corner. We called it “Don’t look to far for culture”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We put the sentence on everyday objects like tote bags, stickers and coasters, so that people would link the MSK with going on vacation when living their normal life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to that, we made a web application that creates your “vacation” through the MSK. You have to choose 3 countries where you like the culture of or would like to go, the app calculates how much you need to travel to get there. Luckily the MSK is just around the corner and you get a personal tour from the website to your likings.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We started with interviewing people in the streets of Ghent and asked about what they knew about the MSK, and what their interests were in general.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">xPuff</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/11/kickstarter.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="xPuff" /><published>2017-05-11T15:28:47+02:00</published><updated>2017-05-11T15:28:47+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/11/kickstarter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/11/kickstarter.html">&lt;p&gt;I searched about 2 days for a project that would be suited for the assignment, eventually I found the xPuff project. It’s a mechanism that filters noise of the surroundings, that you attach on your apple earpods microphone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created sketches of how I saw the flow of the video and of all the scenes there had to be. I wanted to create a story about a character that has trouble calling his friend, and show the positive points of using the xPuff. But I wanted to create an imaginary character, it didn’t had to look ‘realistic’, it was placed in a fantasy world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started with creating the scenery, all the different objects, and the character in illustrator, then I imported everything in after effects and started to animate everything. The first weeks I made a solid foundation of the motion video, I made a script for the voice-over and looked for a suiting song. The first version was synced on the music and voice-over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got feedback and started to adjust the animation to the feedback that I got, I placed minor animations in the details, and tweaked everything until the movements of the character looked natural and I was satisfied with the result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a long and difficult assignment, but I liked working on it, making everything perfect how I want it. And creating a project that I can be proud of.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I searched about 2 days for a project that would be suited for the assignment, eventually I found the xPuff project. It’s a mechanism that filters noise of the surroundings, that you attach on your apple earpods microphone.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tribute freddie mercury</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/04/24/tribute.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tribute freddie mercury" /><published>2017-04-24T15:28:47+02:00</published><updated>2017-04-24T15:28:47+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/24/tribute</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/04/24/tribute.html">&lt;p&gt;Freddie Mercury seemed the most logical option for us, because we were able to find a lot of content and so we would be able to make a story around his life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We struggled a bit with the Design at first, we couldn’t really find a design that would be different then the others, it was to simple, so we decided to start over, and go in a whole other direction. The design we eventually came up with, was insprired on Spotify’s duo-tone effect, we decided to combine it with shapes and fitting colors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the development part of the project, I focused myself on the soundbar React component, the CSS and JS part, and making the website responsive. While Benoit did html, the bottom React component, and basic css.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Freddie Mercury seemed the most logical option for us, because we were able to find a lot of content and so we would be able to make a story around his life.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dok Gent</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/01/20/dokgent.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dok Gent" /><published>2017-01-20T14:28:47+01:00</published><updated>2017-01-20T14:28:47+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/01/20/dokgent</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/01/20/dokgent.html">&lt;p&gt;When I started with the assignment, I wanted to try a whole different style for the design as I was used to do, I wanted to challenge myself to go out of my comfort zone and try something new. That’s how I came up with a design with allot of shapes that supports the content and I used allot of colours instead of keeping it simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first week I struggled with the structure of the design, how everything should be placed, what I would place on the home screen, and what should be on the detail page. When I knew what I would place where, I created wireframes for web and mobile and I build up the database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I started designing, I struggled with the new direction I wanted to take, everything ‘screamed’ to much for attention, and the structure didn’t seem all right. So I made a couple different variations of the design until I was happy. The colours of the events were different depending on the location of where they were held. I placed the 2 next upcoming events on the home page, found a filter system that would work, and placed recommendations and the next similar event on the detail page of an event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transferring the design in code was a task that took me about 5 days. I came across different challenging parts where I really had to stop and think about how I should code them. I eventually finished the project, got everything to work nicely, and was happy that I took another direction. It was a challenging but fun project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly enough, the website doesn’t work anymore because the school emptied the databases, and I have an error now. But I made an Invision mockup, so you can still see all the aspects of the website.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When I started with the assignment, I wanted to try a whole different style for the design as I was used to do, I wanted to challenge myself to go out of my comfort zone and try something new. That’s how I came up with a design with allot of shapes that supports the content and I used allot of colours instead of keeping it simple.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">orca game</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/01/11/orcagame.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="orca game" /><published>2017-01-11T14:28:47+01:00</published><updated>2017-01-11T14:28:47+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/01/11/orcagame</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/01/11/orcagame.html">&lt;p&gt;During the first week we started gathering assets and a concept for the game in a group of 2, when the concept was clear, we started coding the game. We (Me and Wouter) came up with a concept about an endless runner game, with enemies that spawn that you have to dodge or kill. But we didn’t wanted you to be able to just press ‘x’ to shoot. We wanted to make it harder then that for the player. So we decided that you were given 2 random letters on the screen. To be able to fire, you had to press these letters simultaneously, every time you fired, the letters would be generated again. Making it harder and more challenging than a normal game. Also, the longer you played the game, the faster the enemies spawned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started to really make it our game, and loved every bit of it. But to all this came an end, we had to switch our  games in progress with another team, so we got the game of Eva and Chloë. It was a game about an orca, that had to dodge land and obstacles, get oxygen by jumping above sea-level in order not to die, and died when it hit the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We added different power ups, created a live system so you don’t die immediately when you hit an obstacle, made everything spawn faster the longer you played the game, did some improvements to the code and created a leaderboard system.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">During the first week we started gathering assets and a concept for the game in a group of 2, when the concept was clear, we started coding the game. We (Me and Wouter) came up with a concept about an endless runner game, with enemies that spawn that you have to dodge or kill. But we didn’t wanted you to be able to just press ‘x’ to shoot. We wanted to make it harder then that for the player. So we decided that you were given 2 random letters on the screen. To be able to fire, you had to press these letters simultaneously, every time you fired, the letters would be generated again. Making it harder and more challenging than a normal game. Also, the longer you played the game, the faster the enemies spawned.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">google doodle</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/01/09/googledoodle.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="google doodle" /><published>2017-01-09T14:28:47+01:00</published><updated>2017-01-09T14:28:47+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/01/09/googledoodle</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/01/09/googledoodle.html">&lt;p&gt;When we were given the assignment we had to look for a holiday that we wanted to use as a theme for the animation. I chose Chinese new-year as holiday, the Chinese culture has always fascinated me and I was excited to start the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Chinese new-year has different symbolic attributes that they use during the holiday, like fortune cookies, oranges etc. I used those elements to create letters and make them come in the screen in a logic and fun way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a very fun project and I learned allot during the project about after effects.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When we were given the assignment we had to look for a holiday that we wanted to use as a theme for the animation. I chose Chinese new-year as holiday, the Chinese culture has always fascinated me and I was excited to start the project.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">blauw</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/11/19/blauw.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="blauw" /><published>2016-11-19T14:28:47+01:00</published><updated>2016-11-19T14:28:47+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/11/19/blauw</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/11/19/blauw.html">&lt;p&gt;For this project I came up with a concept, where the winners would win a rooftop party sponsored by Blauw. For the website I wanted to recreate a realistic building, with a rooftop party on it. The building is full with blue elements and boards that give them the info they need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to win the contest they had to send in a picture of their group where everything is blue, clothes, hair, the setting etc. The concept was ‘Blauw brings the roof to you’ They also had to send in how they want to end their perfect rooftop party, and if they win, this wish would be fulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was very happy with the result of the website, it was a challenge to make everything look as realistic as possible and make everything look right.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For this project I came up with a concept, where the winners would win a rooftop party sponsored by Blauw. For the website I wanted to recreate a realistic building, with a rooftop party on it. The building is full with blue elements and boards that give them the info they need.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The jetsetters festival</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/06/10/trucks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The jetsetters festival" /><published>2016-06-10T15:28:47+02:00</published><updated>2016-06-10T15:28:47+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/06/10/trucks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/06/10/trucks.html">&lt;p&gt;As a concept for the assignment I chose to make an exclusive event for rich people, a truck festival with airplanes on a private airport. The visitors had to option win a meeting with bill gates, win a concept car, have a swim in a swimming pool filled with champagne etc. the festival was extravagant and not for everybody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the ticket system we had to keep all the data in a database, and place orders in them. I made a countdown of how many tickets were left in total, because the event was limited to 100 tickets. Design wise I wanted to experiment with putting pictures inside of 3d cubes. And I made the tickets look like airplane tickets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a hard project for me at the time because I was struggling with PHP, but I managed to make everything work, and was happy with the result.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">As a concept for the assignment I chose to make an exclusive event for rich people, a truck festival with airplanes on a private airport. The visitors had to option win a meeting with bill gates, win a concept car, have a swim in a swimming pool filled with champagne etc. the festival was extravagant and not for everybody.</summary></entry></feed>